cloudconvert.com 2019-12-08

# Privacy Policy | CloudConvert

June 28, 2018

Our service can only exist if our customers can be sure that their data is safe. Thus, privacy has the highest priority for us. To be transparent we will explain in more detail how CloudConvert handles your data in the following. 

CloudConvert is maintained by Lunaweb GmbH, Gruenwald (Germany). As a Data Controller, CloudConvert is bound by the requirements of the General Data Protection Regulations (GDPR). If you do not agree to our Privacy Policy and the other terms stated below, please do not use our services and let us know about your concerns. We reserve the right to change our Privacy Policy and other terms stated below at any time. If changes occur, we will clearly indicate such alterations at the top of this page with the date of modification. 

**June 28, 2018:** Added information about sharing data with our support ticket system Freshdesk. 

**May 9, 2018:** General clarifications and adjustemnts regarding the GDPR. In particular we added detailed information about your rights and about sharing your data. 

**January 25, 2016:** We have completely reworked our privacy policy with more details about third party plugins, our security mechanisms, and handling your personal data in general. 

### Personal Data Collected by Us

We collect the minimum amount of necessary data only. If you register, buy or subscribe for services, we need to collect more data about you. We do not collect any data from your uploaded files. 

By visiting our website and/or using our API, your IP address will be logged along with the HTTP referrer, user agent and the dates of access (log data). 

By providing a file for conversion, we **do not** read or collect file content, metadata or other data from your uploaded files. For statistical purposes, we do collect the number of converted files, the number of errors and the total file size of all your conversions only. 

If you decide to create a CloudConvert account, we collect your eMail address, your chosen username and your profile picture. If you use our contact form, we collect your eMail address and your name. 

If you decide to buy a package or to subscribe, we need to additionally collect your full name, physical address, company name and VAT id. We do not collect your credit card data. All financial transactions are handled through our payment provider [Stripe](https://www.stripe.com/). Before providing any personal data to Stripe, please make sure that you have read their privacy policies. 

### Use of Your Personal Data

We use your personal data to provide our service only. We do not make profiles or stuff like that. 

We do log your IP address to prevent abuse of our service and for broad demographic analysis. We do not link this information to any personally identifiable information. 

If you provide an eMail address we use it to communicate with according to your [notification settings](https://cloudconvert.com/settings/notifications). 

If you buy a package or subscribe for our services your name, company and address is used to create the invoice and for prevention of fraud. Your VAT id may be used to check if you qualify to exempt of paying VAT. 

### Handling of Your Files

We do not look into it. You can delete your uploaded files at anytime. We do not make any copies. 

In the course of providing the service your files are transferred to and temporary stored on servers of CloudConvert. We **do not** read, look into or mine any data from your files or its metadata. We do not make any copies of it. All file processing is done by machine and there is no human interaction with your files. Your files are deleted immediately and irreversible from our servers when you click the "×" icon (on the right beside the Download button). This will happen automatically at the latest after 24 hours. 

### Sharing Your Data

We do not share your files. We do need to share some of your personal data in order to provide you with services. 

Your uploaded files will not be given out our sold to anyone. No one, you did not provide the download link, will ever have access to your uploaded or converted files. 

Also, your username, email and profile picture or other account data will not be shared with anyone. 

If you buy a package or if you subscribe, we need to send your name and your address to our payment provider [Stripe](https://www.stripe.com/), which is based outside the European Union. This is necessary to process the payment and to prevent fraud. Before providing any personal data to Stripe, please make sure that you have read their privacy policies. 

If use the contact form or if you mail us, we send your name, email address and message to our ticket system [Freshdesk](https://freshdesk.com/). Freshdesk is based outside the European Union. 

### Keeping your Data

Files are deleted after 24h at latest. We keep your personal data until it is needed for the provision of our services. 

We will keep your personal data for as long as it is necessary to provide you with our services. Your files are deleted immediately and irreversible from our servers when use the delete button. This will happen automatically at the latest after 24 hours. 

If you delete your account, all personal data will be permanently deleted within 72 hours. All log data (IP address, user agent, referrer) is deleted after 14 days. 

### Your Rights

You can modify or delete your data on your own at anytime. 

Your can modify your data on your [dashboard](https://cloudconvert.com/settings/profile). You can [delete your account](https://cloudconvert.com/delete) at anytime on your own. This will delete your account and all associated data permanently within 72 hours. Deleting your account also deletes all data stored at payment provider Stripe and ticket system Freshdesk (if there is any). Alternatively, you can contact us and we will do it for you. 

Please note that your uploaded files are automatically deleted after 24 hours at latest. You can manually delete files from our servers when you click the "×" icon (on the right beside the Download button). 

You have the right to be given a copy of information held by us about you. We will provide the requested information to you within 40 calendar days of the receipt of a valid request in writing. We might request you to provide additional information to enable us to identify your personal data and/or to verify your identity. 

### Security

We do a lot to protect your data and make our service as secure as possible. We keep your files in the European Union. 

We are committed to protect your personal data and your files. CloudConvert takes all necessary measures to keep your personal information and your files private and secure. The CloudConvert staff is trained in order to properly handle your data. All third-party employees who have access to your personal information have signed data processing agreements. 

CloudConvert maintains a secure IT environment and all security measures are constantly adjusted to technical progress. All transfers from and to CloudConvert are SSL encrypted. All CloudConvert servers are located in the European Union and have the appropriate measures in place to prevent unauthorised access (i.e. hacking). To explain our security measurements in detail would be too extensive for this page; if you want to get more details about our security concept please feel free to contact us. 

### Cookies

We need them to provide our services. 

CloudConvert stores so-called cookies in order to be able to offer you a comprehensive range of functions and to make it easier to use our websites. Cookies are small files which are stored on your computer with the help of the internet browser. If you do not want to use cookies, you can prevent cookies from being stored on your computer using the corresponding settings on your internet browser. Please note that this may restrict the functional capability and the range of functions of our offer. 

### Analytics

We do use Google Analytics on this site. You can opt out if you do not like it. 

We use Google Analytics to store information about how visitors use our website so that we may make improvements and give visitors a better user experience. Google Analytics is a third-party information storage system by Google that records information about the pages you visit, the length of time you were on specific pages and the website in general, how you arrived at the site and what you clicked on. You can [opt out](http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout) of the usage of Google Analytics on this and all other websites using a browser plugin.
